Let's now see our results side by side.
이제 결과를 나란히 보죠
We started our journey with a constant model that was at $1.46 error from the average of all of the
1달러짜리 모델로 여정을 시작했어요 데이터 평균에서 46개 오류예요
data.
훈련 데이터 세트에서 전통적인 머신 러닝 모델을 봤습니다 몇 가지 기능만 있었죠
It got to 1.39.
1까지 갔어요 39살요
It beat the average random forest.
일반적인 숲을 능가하죠
The best of our traditional machine learning models got to 97.
전통적인 머신 러닝 모델 중 최고는 97점이었어요
The human got to 127, GPT four got to 76, and our fine tuned customized model has got us to $47.
참가자는 127점을 받았고 GPT는 4점을 받았습니다 미세하게 개조한 모델은 47점을 받았죠
And this, of course, brings me to the challenge for you.
그래서 여러분에게 도전 과제를 드리려고 해요
The challenge for you is to improve on this $47.
47달러를 더 벌어야 해요
Uh, this is something where hyperparameter optimization can go a long way.
하이퍼파라미터 최적화가 큰 도움이 될 거예요
And so the task at hand is now to play with the hyperparameters experiment, use weights and biases.
이제 하이퍼파라미터 실험을 진행할 차례입니다 무게와 바이어스를 사용하는 작업이죠
Uh, explore maybe different optimizers, different learning rates, different batch sizes, and see
다양한 최적화 방법과 학습률 다양한 배치 크기를 고려해서 이 수치를
what you can do to improve on this number.
개선할 방법을 찾아보세요
You can also explore different ways of running the model at inference time to see if that improves it.
모델을 추론 시간에 실행하는 다양한 방법을 탐구할 수도 있습니다 개선되었는지 보기 위해서요
And then there is one factor that is actually perhaps the way that you can make the the biggest impact
그리고 한 가지 요인이 더 있습니다 결과에 가장 큰 영향을 주는 방법으로 가장 작은 변화도
on the results with the smallest change is to relook one more time at the data set, at the data curation
만들 수 있는 거죠 데이터 세트와 데이터 큐레이션 단계를 다시 한 번 살펴보고
step, and challenge yourself to see whether you can think of different ways to be prompting or organizing
정보를 프레젠테이션하거나 조직화하는 다양한 방법을 생각할 수 있는지
that information in order to be getting better outcomes.
도전하는 거예요 더 나은 결과를 위해서요
And then there is one final thing that you could do, which is a bigger step, but very exciting.
마지막으로 할 수 있는 게 하나 더 있어요 더 큰 단계지만 아주 흥미진진하죠
And if you don't do it, I'm definitely going to do it, which is to try the other models on this.
안 하면 제가 할 거예요 다른 모델도 써 보려고요
Try Jama, try Kwon the powerhouse, try fi three, see how they perform.
JAM이나 권 장군을 써봐요 어떻게 하는지 보자고요
There are a couple of places where it might be a bit fiddly, because they might not predict one token
좀 성가신 부분도 있어요 토큰 하나가 올바른 숫자라는 예측을 못 할 수도
as the right number, just maybe that's only at that inference function.
있거든요 비트는 추론 함수에서만 가능하니까요
Otherwise everything else might just be fine.
그것만 빼면 다 괜찮을 거예요
But you'll need to experiment with that and convince yourself that it's that it's so good.
하지만 실험해 보고 맛있다고 자신을 설득해야 해요
So try some different models.
다른 모델도 시도해 보세요
You could also try doing the whole thing with a version of llama three that's quantized to eight bits
라마3를 전체 버전으로 만들어도 돼요 4비트가 아니라 8비트로 수량화한
instead of four bits, depending on your appetite for that.
거죠 여러분의 입맛에 따라서요
There are also some larger models.
큰 모델도 있어요
There is a version of 53, I think that is 14 billion parameters that you could experiment with and
53번 버전도 있어요 140억 개의 매개 변수를 실험해보고 개선되는지
see whether that improves things.
볼 수 있죠
So that is the objective.
그게 목표예요
I would love to hear from the first person that can get this below 40.
Get 4만 이하로 맞추는 첫 번째 분께 듣고 싶네요
That has to be possible.
그게 가능해야 해요
I think there is like a hard limit on how low you can get it, given the reality of uncertainty in pricing,
불확실한 가격을 생각하면 얼마나 낮출 수 있는지에 엄격한 제한이 있는 것 같아요 하지만
but I think you guys, someone is going to be able to get it below $40.
누군가는 40달러 이하로 낮출 수 있을 거예요 Get it
You'll build a model that can get within $40 across the 251st items in the test set, and I can't wait
테스트 세트에서 251번째 아이템에 대해 40달러 이내로 접근할 수 있는 모델을 구축합니다. 빨리 들어보고
to hear about that.
싶네요.
So please do reach out and tell me when you get below 40, and tell me your hyperparameters and your
그러니 40 이하로 떨어지면 연락 주세요 hyperpaameter와 모델을
model so that I can try and recreate it myself.
알려 주시면 제가 직접 만들어 볼게요
I would love that.
그럼 좋죠
And with that, let's wrap up for the week.
이것으로 이번 주를 마무리하죠
It's the end now of week seven where you can now do, of course, obviously generating text and code
7주 차가 끝났으니 이제 프론티어 API로 텍스트와 코드 생성 오픈
with frontier APIs and with open source models and hugging face, you can solve problems including dataset
소스 모델 얼굴 포옹 데이터셋 큐레이션 기본 모델 미세 조정 같은
curation, a baseline model, and fine tuning.
문제를 해결할 수 있죠
And at this point, you can confidently carry out the full process for selecting and training an open
이 시점에서는 전 과정을 자신 있게 수행할 수 있습니다 한계를 뛰어넘을
source model that can outperform the frontier.
오픈 소스 모델을 선택하고 훈련하는 거죠
And that's a big accomplishment.
대단한 성과죠
So next week is the finale of this course, and I promise you, I've kept the best to last.
다음 주에 이 과정의 결승전이 있어요 장담하는데 최고의 요리를 준비했죠
It's going to be a triumph.
대성공일 거예요
Next week is going to be so much fun.
다음 주는 정말 재미있을 거예요
You've you've got this far.
여기까지 왔잖아요
Hang on in there to the very end to see everything come together.
끝까지 버텨서 모든 게 잘 어우러지는 걸 봐야죠
There's some stuff that's really important we're going to do about now packaging up what we've done
우리가 할 아주 중요한 게 몇 가지 있어요 지금까지 한 걸 패키징하고
and being able to deploy it as behind an API so we can use it for production purposes, and then really
API 뒤에서 배포할 수 있도록 하는 거죠 프로덕션 목적으로 사용할 수 있도록요 그런
package everything into an application that can can make a real impact.
다음 모든 걸 응용 프로그램에 패키지하는 거죠 실제 영향을 줄 수 있는 응용 프로그램에요
And at that point, you'll be in a position to be creating your own end to end solutions to commercial
그 시점에 여러분은 상업적 문제에 대한 자신만의 해결책을 만들 수 있는 위치에 서게
problems.
되죠
Using groundbreaking llms that you'll be able to train yourself.
획기적인 llm을 사용해 스스로 훈련할 수 있죠
So there's a lot ahead, and I can't wait for next week.
할 일이 많아요 다음 주가 기대돼요
And as always, I will see you there.
늘 그렇듯 거기서 봐요